Guide to the Carlyle Marney Papers, 1899-1979 RL.00848
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Materials Series, 1959-1978 and undated
  - Reel-to-reel Tapes
    - God is Dead Debate/Discussion, 1966, June. (Box 136, Item R1)
    - Joint Convention of American and Southern Baptists, n. d. (Box 136, Item R9)
    - Keys to the Future, 1962, Sept. 15. (Box 136, Item R10)
    - Laymen's Hour, 1962, Nov. (Box 136, Item R11)
    - Laymen's Hour, 1965, Jan.and Feb. (Box 136, Item R12)
    - Laymen's Hour, 1965, Jan.and Feb. (Box 136, Item R13)
    - Laymen's Hour, 1965, Mar.and Apr. (Box 137, Item R14-15)
    - Laymen's Hour, 1965, Mayand June. (Box 137, Item R16-17)
    - Laymen's Hour, 1965, Julyand Aug. (Box 137, Item R18-19)
    - Laymen's Hour, 1965, Sept.and Oct. (Box 137, Item R20-21)
    - Laymen's Hour, 1965, Nov.and Dec. (Box 137, Item R22-23)
    - Left to Right (sermon), 1959, Jan. 25. (Box 138, Item R24)
    - Man is Free (I and II), 1961, Jan. 8and 15. (Box 138, Item R25)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1957. (Box 138, Item R26-27)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1958. (Box 138, Item R28)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1959. (Box 138, Item R29)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1960. (Box 138, Item R30-31)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1961 (Box 138, Item R32-33)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1962. (Box 138, Item R34-35)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1963. (Box 138, Item R36-37)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1964. (Box 139, Item R38)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1965. (Box 139, Item R39)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1966. (Box 139, Item R40)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1967. (Box 139, Item R41-43)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1968. (Box 139, Item R44-45)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1969. (Box 139, Item R46)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1972. (Box 139, Item R47-51)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1973. (Box 140, Item R52-53)
    - Massanetta Springs Recordings, 1974. (Box 101, Item R54-55)
    - The Meaning of Marriage, n. d. (Box 140, Item R56)
    - Presentations at Georgetown, 1974. (Box 140, Item R57-58)
    - Symposium on Sexuality, n. d. (Box 140, Item R59)
    - This Earth's Precious Fruit, n. d. (Box 140, Item R60)
    - What is the Function of the Sermon?, n. d. (Box 140, Item R61)
    - McFarland, Ken The Best of Ken McFarland's Humor, n. d. (Box 140, Item R64)
    - Misheff, James, Sermon: We Haven't Come to Stay, n. d. (Box 141, Item R65)
    - Trueblood, Siegel, and Weigel, Title unknown, n. d. (Box 141, Item R66)
    - Anonymous, Birmingham: A Testament of Non-violence, 1963, June 3-8. (Box 141, Item R67-72)
    - Anonymous, Democracy in America - the Tyranny of the Majority, n. d. (Box 141, Item R74)
    - Anonymous, Democracy in America - Where Could I be Better Off?, n.d. (Box 141, Item R75)
    - Anonymous, The True Purpose of the White Race, n.d. (Box 141, Item R76)
    - Unknown tape of a woman and children, (see note inside box), n.d. (Box 141, Item R77)
    - PRESERVATION COPIES for reel-to-reels (RESTRICTED: closed to reference use; use copies must be made from these CDs) (Box 145)
    - LISTENING COPIES for reel-to-reels (see individual listings in Reel to Reel series above for use copies that currently exist) (Box 146)
    - PRESERVATION COPIES for cassette tapes (RESTRICTED: closed to reference use; use copies must be made from these CDs) (Box 147)
  - Films
    [Originals CLOSED to use. No use copies are available. Technical Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed. Please contact Research Services staff before coming to use the collection.]
    - Film on Marney's South American trip (Box 142, Item F1)
    - Look Up and Live: The Passing Tradition. (Box 143-144, Item F2-3)
  - Audiovisual Accession 2017-0138, 1
    Conditions Governing Access
    This addition to the collection contains audio cassettes and reels requiring digitization prior to access. Contact Rubenstein Library Research Services for further information on using these resources.
    - Marney 1; Marney 2, undated; 1
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0001)
    - Marney 3; Marney 4, undated; 2
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0002)
    - Marney 5; Marney 6, undated; 3
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0003)
    - Marney 7; Marney 8, undated; 4
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0004)
    - Marney 9; Marney 10, undated; 5
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0005)
    - Marney 11; Marney 12, undated; 6
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0006)
    - Marney 1; Marney 2, undated; 12
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0012)
    - Marney 3; Marney 4, undated; 11
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0011)
    - Marney 5; Marney 6, undated; 14
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0014)
    - Marney 7; Marney 8, undated; 15
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0015)
    - Marney 9; Marney 10, undated; 19
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0019)
    - Marney 11; Marney 12, undated; 18
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0018)
    - Marney: A Proper Sedition; Marney: My Cellar People, undated; 7
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0007)
    - Carlyle Marney: Shall We Die As Fools Die; Carlyle Marney: No Casual Meeting, undated; 8
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0008)
    - Marney: How to Be a Human Being, undated; 9
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0009)
    - Marney: From Freud to Our Present Higher Good, undated; 10
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0010)
    - Carylyle Marney, Ph.D.: "Shall We Die As Fools Die?"; Robert G. Bratcher, Ph.D.: "Tips for Interpreters"; Kenneth E. Bailey, Ph.D.: "The Pharisee and the Publican (Luke 18:9-14)", 1974 September; 13
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0013)
    - Marney Sermon, Currin, 1978 July 9; 16
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0016)
    - Meeting Messiah on the Road, C. Marney; True Believer, C. Marney, undated; 17
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0017)
    - Marney: "Wisdom flirts with madness", 1965; 20
      - Original audiocassette (Box 149, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0020)
    - Marney 2, Copy #2: Faith as Relation; Faith as Process, undated; 21
      - Original audio reel (Box 149, Audio-reel RL00848-RR-0001)
    - Marney 3, Copy #2: Language of Revelation; Language of Conversation, undated; 22
    - Marney 4, Copy #2: To Have, To Do, To Be; The New Shape of Faith, undated; 23
      - Original audio reel (Box 149, Audio-reel RL00848-RR-0003)
  - Audiovisual Accession 2021-0013
    This addition to the collection contains audio reels requiring digitization prior to access. Contact Rubenstein Library Research Services for further information on using these resources.
    - Dr. Carlyle Marney - Massanetta 1971, 5 addresses, 1971-08-08-1971-08-22
      Side 1: 8-8-71, 7:10 pm (Women); 8-10-71, 8:00 pm (The X'n Genius); 8-15-71, 11:00 am (Contemporary Salvation) Side 2: 8-19-71, 8:00 pm (Credo or Creed); 8-22-71, 11:00 am (Sermon - Luke 24)
      - Original audio reel (Box 150, Audio-reel RL00848-RR-0004)
    - Dr. Carlyle Marney - Massanetta 1971, 1971-08-09-1971-08-17
      Introduction to Panel Meetings. Side 1: 8-9-71, 9:00 am, "God"; 8-12-71, 9:00 am, "The Bible"; 8-17-71, 9:00 am, "The Minister as a Parson." Side 2: Not used.
      - Original audio reel (Box 150, Audio-reel RL00848-RR-0005)
    - Dr. Carlyle Marney - The People in My Cellar/The People in my Balcony, 1976-08-19
      Experimental Institute for Human Development, Princeton University, produced by Keith Miller and Bruce Johnson, audio recorded by Bruce Johnson, producer, Word, Incorporated, Waco, Texas.
      - Original audio cassette (Box 150, Audio-cassette RL00848-CS-0021, Audio-cd RL00848-CD-0001, Digital-materials RL00848-SET-0001, Audio-file RL00848-CD-0001_01.wav, Audio-file RL00848-CD-0001_02.wav)